

#### **PERSONAL**

Birthday : 22 November 1983

Status : Single
Nationality : Indian
Languages : English, Hindi

## **Formal Education**

#### **AMITY UNIVERSITY**

PGDM NGO Management 2005 – 2006

### **DELHI UNIVERSITY**

BA Sociology Hons. Jesus & Mary College 2002 – 2005

#### **DPS RK PURAM**

School till 2002

#### SKILLS

COMMUNICATION

PLANNING & ORGANIZING

CRISIS MANAGEMENT

HUMAN RESOURCES MANAGEMENT

PROBLEM IDENTIFICATION & RESOLUTION

PROCEDURE DEVELOPMENT & REFINEMENT

#### CONTACT



9910906077



gunikasinghh@gmail.com



S 278 GK 2 New Delhi – 48, India

# **GUNIKA SINGH**

#### **PROFILE**

13 years of experience in working with children of tops schools across India, Actively delivering outdoor educational programs in the B2B and B2C segment. I am passionate about building leadership in children and is convinced that there is no better apparatus than self-discovery in the outdoors Apart from educating children while travelling with them across the world, I also have been an integral part in assisting the Program development team, heading the Training department of Internal and external staff and managing the Human resource activities of the organization.

# Experience

# EdTerra Edventures Pvt Ltd

Sr- Manager - Human Resource

Dec 2014 - Present

Interfacing with the management and heads of the department for implementing Hr policies Procedures in line with the core organizational objectives.

Executing the entire gamut of task in recruitment encompassing, sourcing, screening selection and appointment etc.

Designing a training plan for all new employees and old employees.

Serve as a link between management and employees by handling questions, interpreting and helping resolve work related problems to foster a positive environment.

Successful in achieving a target in hiring.

Sr. Manager - Domestic Sales & retail Sales

Budgeting and accounting for the financial year

Forecasting Business acquisition plan.

Quality management and control for the sales and delivery of the product.

Handling the Delhi market.

Responsible for Primary and secondary sales.

Designing and changing the product according to the market demands.

Responsible for preparing market strategies and schemes to counter Competitors activity in market.

Travel educator:

Designing and developing the tools for study for children for different destinations within India and abroad.

Travel and handle operations for student groups to USA, Europe.

# Youreka – Outdoor Education division of iDiscoveri

Marketing / Sales

Feb 2007 - 2014 Nov

Client Interaction and direct selling of programs. Working on marketing initiative through social networking sites. Gathering updated database of the prospective clients and preparing monthly emailers.

Customer Relationship Management Software

Developed CRM software for tracking and recording client database. Also, preparing periodic reports, financial statements and records on program activities, progress, status and other reports for management. Recruiting and training client interaction staff.

Managing the call centre

clients into actual customers. Ensure all official documents are reaching the leads timely and no ambiguity left between interaction and understanding.

Client Co-ordination

Communicating, interacting and maintaining liaison with parents, children and school faculty for planning and facilitating program objectives. Ensuring client satisfaction by providing advice and problem solving assistance related to the program. Maintaining customer's wish list and delivering as promised.

**Escorting Groups** 

Accompanying individual and groups on international programs in London, Singapore, Spain and nationally in Himachal Pradesh, Uttaranchal, and Tamil Nadu, Singapore, London. Working on cost involved for outstation customers coming for national programs or international programs.

Accounting for Programs

Budgeting per program with main focus on saving but not compromising. Maintaining expense tracker for the programs. Cash handling, rechecking claims with the actual and maintaining proper records.

HR

Hiring and outsourcing instructors for outdoors.